Ruth Krauss Papers
© 2004 University of Connecticut
- Series VIII: Poetry, undated, 1958-1988
  - "Poem on Poem" [tss and copies], undated (Box 40:, Folder 1302)
  - Poem play collection, unidentified, undated (Box 40:, Folder 1303)
  - Poem play collections [cover materials], undated (Box 40:, Folder 1304)
  - Poem plays [notes], undated (Box 40:, Folder 1305)
  - Poem plays, unidentified [tss], undated (Box 40:, Folder 1306)
  - "Poem Poem" [tss and copy], 1969 December (Box 40:, Folder 1307)
  - "Poem-Script" [copy], undated (Box 40:, Folder 1308)
  - "Poem-Strip-Act" [tss and mss], undated (Box 40:, Folder 1309)
  - Poems (unpublished collection) [tss and copies], 1971? December (Box 40:, Folder 1310)
  - "Poems for a Pony"
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 40:, Folder 1311)
    - Undated typescripts (Box 40:, Folder 1312)
    - Manuscript, 1961 November 25 (Box 40:, Folder 1313)
    - Typescript, 1961 October 9 (Box 40:, Folder 1314)
    - Typescripts and copies, 1961 November 27 (Box 40:, Folder 1315)
    - Typescript, 1961 December 18 (Box 40:, Folder 1316)
  - Poems for Poets (unpublished collection) [tss and copies, undated (Box 40:, Folder 1317)
  - Poems Using Worn-Out Words
    - Typescripts, undated (Box 40:, Folder 1318)
    - Typescripts and manuscripts, 1967 August (Box 40:, Folder 1319)
  - Poetic bibliography, partial, undated (Box 40:, Folder 1320)
  - "Poetry" [copy], undated (Box 40:, Folder 1321)
  - Poetry catalogs, 1981 (Box 40:, Folder 1322)
  - Poetry newspaper clippings, 1988 (Box 40:, Folder 1323)
  - Poetry workshop assignments
    - Fall 1958 - Spring 1959, 1958-1959 (Box 41:, Folder 1324)
    - Stream of consciousness, ca. 1959-1960 (Box 41:, Folder 1325)
    - Folder 1, undated (Box 41:, Folder 1326)
    - Folder 2, ca. 1960 (Box 41:, Folder 1327)
    - Folder 3, ca. 1960 (Box 41:, Folder 1328)
    - Folder 4, ca. 1959-1960 (Box 41:, Folder 1329)
    - Folder 5, ca. 1959-1960 (Box 41:, Folder 1330)
  - "Pony Idyll" [tss, mss, copies, layout sketch], undated (Box 41:, Folder 1331)
  - "Prelude and Song" [tss and copy], undated (Box 41:, Folder 1332)
  - "Pretty Word Hour" [copy], undated (Box 41:, Folder 1333)
  - "Private Poem in Public Places" [tss and copies], undated (Box 41:, Folder 1334)
  - "Project: Take an Island" [tss and copy], undated (Box 41:, Folder 1335)
  - Prose poems [tss and copies], undated (Box 41:, Folder 1336)
  - "Punctuation Lessons" [mss], undated (Box 41:, Folder 1337)
  - "Putting a Spell On" [tss and mss], undated (Box 41:, Folder 1338)
  - "Quartet" [unpublished poem], undated (Box 41:, Folder 1339)
  - "Questions or Perhaps Answers" [tss and copy], undated (Box 41:, Folder 1340)
  - "Quickie" [tss], undated (Box 41:, Folder 1341)
  - "Rape" (partial) [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1342)
  - "Rebellion against the White Lace North" [tss], 1961 February 16 (Box 42:, Folder 1343)
  - "The Realiste" [tss and copies], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1344)
  - "Recipe" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1345)
  - Re-examination of Freedom (show) [tss, mss, notes], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1346)
  - Refound Poems (unpublished collection) [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1347)
  - "Reverdy in Nutshell" [copy], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1348)
  - "Reverie for a Star" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1349)
  - "Riddles in Poetry" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1350)
  - "River of Light and Dark" [tss and mss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1351)
  - "Romeo and Juliet" [tss and copies], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1352)
  - Ron Glass anthology, undated (Box 42:, Folder 1353)
  - "Room with a Lost Beginning"/"When It Is Dark" [tss and copies], ca. May 1968 (Box 42:, Folder 1354)
  - "A Round" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1355)
  - Ruthie Illuminated [tss and copies], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1356)
  - "Sad" [tss, copies, drafts], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1357)
  - "Salt Marsh Song" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1358)
  - "Salutation and Farewell" [tss and mss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1359)
  - "The Sea at the End of the Alley" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1360)
  - Sestinas, undated (Box 42:, Folder 1361)
  - "Sestina: Hans Christian What" [annotated tss], April 1962 (Box 42:, Folder 1362)
  - "Sestina to the Sun" [tss and mss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1363)
  - Seven Poem Plays (unpublished collection) [tss and dates], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1364)
  - Seven Theater Poems (unpublished collection)
    - Layout sketch, undated (Box 42:, Folder 1365)
    - Sketches, undated (Box 42:, Folder 1366)
  - "She" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1367)
  - "Shoes Made of Dawn" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1368)
  - "Short Poem" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1369)
  - "Short Poem Long Notes" [tss and copies], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1370)
  - "Sing Song" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1371)
  - "Sky Poems" [tss and copy], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1372)
  - "Small Stinkin Play" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1373)
  - "Solo and City" [tss and copies], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1374)
  - "Somebody's Mother" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1375)
  - "Somehow Connected with Lorca" [tss; See also "In Celebration of Tricycle and Scissorgrinder Week."], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1376)
  - "Somersault Sonnet" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1377)
  - "Something Wonderful Happens When You... " [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1378)
  - "Sometimes" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1379)
  - "Song and Act" [tss, mss, copies], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1380)
    See also "Duet" (unpublished poem).
  - "Song and Dance" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1381)
  - "Song and Refrain" [tss and copies], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1382)
  - "Song: Apologies to Someone" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1383)
  - "Song Blue" [tss], undated (Box 42:, Folder 1384)
  - Song Collection (partial), undated (Box 42:, Folder 1385)
  - "Song, Connected to Susan" [tss and copy], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1386)
  - "Song for Simpleton" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1387)
  - "Song for the New, the Young, the Incorrigible" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1388)
  - "Song: not for Annie" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1389)
  - "Song of the Aviator" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1390)
  - "Song of the Colt" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1391)
  - "Song to Make the Man Behave" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1392)
  - "Song Why is the Trestle" [partial tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1393)
  - "Song: With Myself" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1394)
  - Song Fiesta (unpublished collection) [contents list and notes], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1395)
  - Songs, Etc. (unpublished collection) [tss and copies], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1396)
  - "Songs for Volcano, Heartbeat, and Guitar" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1397)
  - "Sonnet-Show" [mss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1398)
  - "Spell-Lesson Song" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1399)
  - "Stage-Poem" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1400)
  - "Stolen Lines" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1401)
  - "Storm" [tss and copies], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1402)
  - "Strange Girl" [tss and copies], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1403)
  - "The Stranger" [tss and copies], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1404)
  - "A Street I Know" [mss]], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1405)
  - "Streetwork" [mss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1406)
  - "Strip Tease" [tss and copies], August 1966 (Box 43:, Folder 1407)
  - "The Suburbs of Physics" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1408)
  - "The Sun is Freaking Out" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1409)
  - "The Sun is My Son" [tss and copies], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1410)
  - "Tail the By Caught Desire" [copy], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1411)
  - "Tailpiece" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1412)
  - "Tentative Haiku-or-Thereabouts Collection" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1413)
  - "The" [tss, mss, copies], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1414)
  - Theater Poems
    - Compilation A, undated (Box 43:, Folder 1415)
    - Compilation B, undated (Box 43:, Folder 1416)
    - Compilation C, undated (Box 43:, Folder 1417)
    - Compilation D, undated (Box 43:, Folder 1418)
  - Theater Presentation, proposed poems, undated (Box 43:, Folder 1419)
  - "Theatre!" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1420)
  - "Theatre in the Round of Night" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1421)
  - Theatre Pieces and Songs (unpublished collection) [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1422)
  - "Them Who" [tss and copy], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1423)
  - "There" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1424)
  - "There Was Snow in Summer" [tss and copy], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1425)
  - There's a Little Ambiguity Over There Among the Bluebells
    - Contents lists, undated (Box 43:, Folder 1426)
    - "Advice for the Casting of a Lake" [tss; Early version of "There's a Little Ambiguity over There among the Bluebells."], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1427)
    - "Ballet for Peaches" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1428)
    - "Complaint" [mss and tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1429)
    - "Dante and the Poet" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1430)
    - "Derangement" [tss], undated (Box 43:, Folder 1431)
    - "Drunk Boat"
      - Undated typescripts (Box 43:, Folder 1432)
      - Dated typescripts, 1968 October - 1969 April (Box 43:, Folder 1433)
    - "Horse-Opera-With-Wings"
      - Title pages and sketches, undated (Box 44:, Folder 1434)
      - Manuscripts, undated (Box 44:, Folder 1435)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 44:, Folder 1436)
    - "Imitation" [tss], undated (Box 44:, Folder 1437)
    - "Miracle, or Goodbye My Poets' Storefront" [tss], 1966 March 2 (Box 44:, Folder 1438)
    - "Wash Day Miracle" [tss; Early version of "Narcissus."], 1964 (Box 44:, Folder 1439)
    - "Narcissus" [tss], undated (Box 44:, Folder 1440)
    - "News"
      - Early versions for poetry workshop, undated (Box 44:, Folder 1442)
      - Typescripts and manuscripts, undated (Box 44:, Folder 1443)
      - Typescripts from class, 1959 Spring (Box 44:, Folder 1444)
      - Typescript, 1968 July (Box 44:, Folder 1445)
    - "Onward" [tss], undated (Box 44:, Folder 1446)
    - Poem Plays
      - Drafts, undated (Box 44:, Folder 1447)
      - Manuscripts, undated (Box 44:, Folder 1448)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 44:, Folder 1449)
    - "Practical Mother's Guide" [tss and copies], undated (Box 44:, Folder 1450)
    - "Quartet"
      - Notes, undated (Box 44:, Folder 1451)
      - Undated typescripts and manuscripts (Box 44:, Folder 1452)
      - Typescript and manuscript, 1962 March 1 (Box 44:, Folder 1453)
    - "Questions or Maybe Answers"
      - Early versions, undated (Box 44:, Folder 1454)
      - Typescripts and manuscripts, ca. 1967 (Box 44:, Folder 1455)
    - "Re-Examination of Freedom"
      - Early drafts, undated (Box 45:, Folder 1456)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 45:, Folder 1457)
      - Annotated copy, undated (Box 45:, Folder 1458)
      - Reworking [tss; See also Under Twenty Ways of Looking at Freedom.], undated (Box 45:, Folder 1459)
    - "A Show, a Play: It's a Girl!" [tss], undated (Box 45:, Folder 1460)
    - "Song" ["When Your Boyfriend Writes You a Letter"] [tss], undated (Box 45:, Folder 1461)
    - "There's a Little Ambiguity Over There Among the Bluebells" [tss, mss, notes], undated (Box 45:, Folder 1462)
    - "Trio"
      - Early versions [tss], undated (Box 45:, Folder 1463)
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 45:, Folder 1464)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 45:, Folder 1465)
      - Layout sketches for book, undated (Box 45:, Folder 1466)
      - Partial book dummies, undated (Box 45:, Folder 1467)
    - "Weather" [tss], undated (Box 45:, Folder 1468)
    - Early compilation of poems, undated (Box 45:, Folder 1469)
    - Typescript, undated (Box 45:, Folder 1470)
    - Typescript with editor's layout marks, undated (Box 45:, Folder 1471)
    - Printer's typescript, undated (Box 45:, Folder 1472)
    - Partial galley, first revision, undated (Box 45:, Folder 1473)
    - Galleys, ca. 1968 February (Box 55:, Folder 1690)
    - Hardware Poets Playhouse, program, undated (Box 45:, Folder 1474)
    - Programs for theater productions, 1973 March (Box 45:, Folder 1475)
    - Reviews of theater productions, 1973 March - April (Box 45:, Folder 1476)
    - Libretto for cantata, undated (Box 45:, Folder 1477)
    - Dust jackets, ca. 1968 (Box 45:, Folder 1478)
    - Clippings, ca. 1968 (Box 45:, Folder 1479)
    - Reviews, ca. 1968 (Box 45:, Folder 1480)
  - "Things that Go Away and Come Back Again" [mss], undated (Box 45:, Folder 1481)
  - ["Thinking of You"] [tss and mss], undated (Box 45:, Folder 1482)
  - This Breast Gothic
    - Notes, undated (Box 46:, Folder 1483)
    - Credits, ca. 1973 (Box 46:, Folder 1483a)
    - Contents lists, undated (Box 46:, Folder 1484)
    - Partial typescript A [tss and copies], undated (Box 46:, Folder 1485)
    - Partial typescript B [tss], undated (Box 46:, Folder 1486)
    - Partial typescript C [tss], undated (Box 46:, Folder 1487)
    - Early compilation [tss and notes], undated (Box 46:, Folder 1488)
    - Typescript, undated (Box 46:, Folder 1489)
    - Printer's typescript, annotated, ca. November 1973 (Box 46:, Folder 1490)
    - "Graffito" and "Graffita" [tss and mss], undated (Box 46:, Folder 1491)
    - "Harp Section" [tss], undated (Box 46:, Folder 1492)
    - "I Feel Like It" [tss], undated (Box 46:, Folder 1493)
    - "I Need You Like" [tss and copies], undated (Box 46:, Folder 1494)
    - "Silence" [mss], undated (Box 46:, Folder 1495)
    - "This Breast"
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 46:, Folder 1496)
      - "Lost Section from This Breast" [mss], undated (Box 46:, Folder 1497)
      - "Lost Sections" [tss], undated (Box 46:, Folder 1498)
      - "This Breast Coda" [tss], undated (Box 46:, Folder 1499)
      - Working copy, 1963 (Box 46:, Folder 1500)
      - Typescript, 3 June 1963 (Box 46:, Folder 1501)
      - "Lost Sections" [tss], January 1965 (Box 46:, Folder 1502)
    - "Weather" [tss], undated (Box 46:, Folder 1503)
    - "When" [tss], undated (Box 46:, Folder 1504)
    - Partial dummy, undated (Box 46:, Folder 1505)
    - "Mixed-up dummy" [copy and notes], undated (Box 46:, Folder 1506)
    - Signature illustrations, undated (Box 46:, Folder 1507)
    - Illustrations of women, undated (Box 46:, Folder 1508)
    - "Love" illustrations by Krauss, undated (Box 46:, Folder 1509)
      See also "Love and the Invention of Punctuation."
    - Acknowledgements, undated (Box 46:, Folder 1510)
    - Cover sketches, undated (Box 46:, Folder 1511)
    - Original printer's dummy with additions by Krauss [copy], ca. 1973 (Box 46:, Folder 1512)
    - Printing notes, ca. 1973 (Box 46:, Folder 1513)
    - Partial Galley and notes, undated (Box 55:, Folder 1685)
    - Proofs, undated (Box 55:, Folder 1686)
    - Unidentified materials, undated (Box 46:, Folder 1514)
  - "This Cabbage" [tss], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1515)
  - "Thoughtful Poem" [mss], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1516)
  - "Three Poems after Reading 'The Reader' by Wallace Stevens" [tss, mss, copies], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1517)
  - "To a Thought" [tss], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1518)
  - "To Prevert" [tss], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1519)
  - "Tom Collins" [penname] collection [tss and mss], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1520)
  - "Travel" [mss], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1521)
  - "Travel Collage" [tss and mss], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1522)
  - "The Tree" [tss and copy], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1523)
  - "Tulips" [tss], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1524)
  - Twelve Songs and a Springtime Musical (unpublished) [tss], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1525)
  - Twenty Ways of Looking at Madison Avenue (unpublished collection) [notes and drafts], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1526)
  - Under 13
    - Proposed titles, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1527)
    - Partial typescript A, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1528)
    - Partial typescript B, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1529)
    - Typescript copies, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1530)
    - "Ten Nos" [tss and mss], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1531)
    - Layout sketch, "Temporary first order,", undated (Box 47:, Folder 1532)
    - Small paste-up dummy and copy, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1533)
    - Large paste-up dummy pages, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1534)
    - Mock-up dummy and copy, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1535)
    - Sketches, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1536)
    - Title page sketches, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1537)
    - Title page for printer [tss and copy], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1538)
    - Instructions to printer, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1539)
    - Annotated photocopy, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1540)
  - Under 20 Ways of Looking at Freedom (unpublished) [tss and copies], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1541)
  - Under 21 (unpublished) [tss], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1542)
  - "Under the Fog of Smyr" [tss and copy], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1543)
  - Under Twenty
    - Contents list, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1544)
    - Partial typescript, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1545)
    - Drafts, folder 1, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1546)
    - Drafts, folder 2, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1547)
    - Drafts, folder 3, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1548)
    - Annotated typescript copy, undated (Box 47:, Folder 1549)
    - "Andy Auto Body", undated
      - "Andy Auto Body," early versions, [tss], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1550)
      - "Andy Auto Body" [tss], undated (Box 47:, Folder 1551)
    - "Dream" ["My dream with its solar pulse gallop"], undated
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1552)
      - Dated typescripts, 1959-1961 (Box 48:, Folder 1553)
    - "Hunting Song" [tss], undated (Box 48:, Folder 1554)
    - "I Love You with the Aid of Brecht" [tss], undated (Box 48:, Folder 1555)
    - "Poem" ["in my black-on-black.. ."] [tss], undated (Box 48:, Folder 1556)
    - "Poem" ["Life"], undated
      - Manuscript, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1557)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1558)
    - "Poem" ["lost, lost"] [tss and mss], undated (Box 48:, Folder 1559)
    - "Poem" ["Where does the river come from"] [tss and mss], undated (Box 48:, Folder 1560)
    - "Poem" ["wits/stars"], undated
      - Manuscripts, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1561)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1562)
    - "Poemplay: A Pillar of Tears" [tss], undated (Box 48:, Folder 1563)
    - "Song" ["Reading about the Wisconsin.. ."], undated
      - "Reading" (early version) [tss], undated (Box 48:, Folder 1564)
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1565)
    - "Tabu", undated
      - Typescripts, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1566)
      - Dated typescripts, 1969 January (Box 48:, Folder 1567)
    - "Variations on a Lorca Form" [tss], undated (Box 48:, Folder 1568)
    - Sketches and copies, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1569)
    - "Flower Children" sketch dummy, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1570)
    - Annotated copy, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1571)
    - ???, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1572)
    - Rejected poems [tss], undated (Box 48:, Folder 1573)
    - Proposed second Under Twenty collection, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1574)
  - "The Undone Poem" [copy], undated (Box 48:, Folder 1575)
  - "The Unfinished Worlds of Ruth Krauss" [tss], undated (Box 48:, Folder 1576)
  - Unidentified dummies, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1577)
  - Unidentified dummy pages, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1578)
  - Unidentified layout sketches, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1579)
  - Unidentified notes, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1580)
  - Unidentified sketches, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1581)
  - Clippings for unidentified works, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1582)
  - Programs for unidentified works, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1583)
  - Fliers for unidentified works, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1584)
  - Unidentified collection of long poems, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1585)
  - Unidentified poetry collections
    - Contents lists, undated (Box 48:, Folder 1586)
    - Collection 1 [tss and copies], undated (Box 48:, Folder 1587)
    - Collection 2 [tss], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1587a)
    - Collection 3 [tss and copies], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1588)
    - Collection 4 [tss and copies], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1589)
    - Collection 5 [dummy], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1590)
    - Collection 6 [tss and copies], 1980 December 8 (Box 49:, Folder 1591)
    - Collection 7 [tss and copies], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1592)
    - Collection 8 [tss and copies], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1593)
    - Collection 9 [tss], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1594)
    - Collection 10 [tss and copies], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1595)
    - Collection 11 [tss and illustrations], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1596)
    - Collection 12 [tss and copies], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1597)
    - Collection 13 [tss and copies], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1598)
    - Collection 14 [contents list and materials], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1598a)
    - Collection 15 [envelope dummy], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1599)
    - Collection 16 [tss and copies], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1600)
    - Collection 17 (incomplete0, undated (Box 49:, Folder 1601)
    - Collection 18 [copies], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1602)
    - Collection 19 [tss and copies], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1603)
    - Collection 20 [tss, copies, notes], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1604)
    - Collection 21 [tss and copies], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1605)
    - Collection 22 [tss and copies], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1606)
    - Collection 23 [copies], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1607)
    - Collection 24 [copies], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1608)
    - Collection 25 [mss, tss, copies, sketches], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1609)
    - Collection 26 [tss], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1610)
    - Collection 27 [tss and copies], undated (Box 49:, Folder 1611)
    - Collection 28 [tss], undated (Box 50:, Folder 1612)
    - Collection 29 [tss and mss], undated (Box 50:, Folder 1613)
    - Collection 30 [contents and partial dummy], undated (Box 50:, Folder 1614)
    - Collection 31 [tss, mss, copies], undated (Box 50:, Folder 1615)
    - Collection 32, "Abandoned," [tss and copies], undated (Box 50:, Folder 1616)
    - Collection 33 [tss and copies], undated (Box 50:, Folder 1617)
    - Collection 34 [tss and copies], undated (Box 50:, Folder 1618)
    - Collection 35 [tss and mss], undated (Box 50:, Folder 1619)
  - The Unrevised Not-Sonnets of Onward Bloom [tss], undated (Box 50:, Folder 1620)
  - Untitled and Unidentified Poems [Includes poems titled "Poem" or "Song" that do not appear in any collection by Krauss, as well as poems without actual titles.]
    - Folder 1, undated (Box 50:, Folder 1621)
    - Folder 2, undated (Box 50:, Folder 1622)
    - Folder 3, undated (Box 50:, Folder 1623)
    - Folder 4, undated (Box 50:, Folder 1624)
    - Folder 5, undated (Box 50:, Folder 1625)
    - Folder 6, undated (Box 51:, Folder 1626)
    - Folder 7, undated (Box 51:, Folder 1627)
    - Folder 8, undated (Box 51:, Folder 1628)
    - Folder 9, undated (Box 51:, Folder 1629)
    - Folder 10, undated (Box 51:, Folder 1630)
    - Folder 11, undated (Box 51:, Folder 1631)
    - Folder 12, undated (Box 52:, Folder 1632)
    - Folder 13, undated (Box 52:, Folder 1633)
    - Folder 14, undated (Box 52:, Folder 1634)
    - Folder 15, undated (Box 52:, Folder 1635)
    - Folder 16, undated (Box 52:, Folder 1636)
    - Folder 17, undated (Box 52:, Folder 1637)
    - Folder 18, undated (Box 53:, Folder 1638)
    - Folder 19, undated (Box 53:, Folder 1639)
    - Folder 20, undated (Box 53:, Folder 1640)
    - Folder 21, undated (Box 53:, Folder 1641)
    - Folder 22, undated (Box 53:, Folder 1642)
    - Related group [drafts], undated (Box 53:, Folder 1643)
  - "Unwaiting for What" [tss and copies], undated (Box 53:, Folder 1644)
  - "Using a Refrain of Audrey Lourdes" [tss], undated (Box 53:, Folder 1645)
  - "Variations" [tss], undated (Box 53:, Folder 1646)
  - "The Voyage of the Henry S" [tss and copies], undated (Box 53:, Folder 1647)
  - "Wagon-Tracks Song" [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1648)
  - "Wandering" [tss], undated (Box 54:, Folder 1649)